A Guide to the Markle Foundation records, Record Group 1-Record Group 3 FA024
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Markle Foundation Administration, 2
  - Markle Foundation Administration - Accession 2, 2; 40.8 Cubic Feet
    - General Office Files, 1968-1992; 2; 15.6 Cubic Feet 13 boxes
      - Alphabetical Files, 1
        - Washington Journalism Review - Robert Kranz, February 1977 (Box 8, Folder 466)
        - Wenner-Gren Foundation, August 16, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 467)
        - Wesleyan University, Connecticut, 1969, 1970, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 468)
        - Western Public Radio, June 1984 (Box 8, Folder 469)
        - Western Reserve University, September 12, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 470)
        - The White House, April 1986 (Box 8, Folder 471)
        - Williams College, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 472)
        - Jerome L. Wilson, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 473)
        - Timothy E. Wirth, October 15, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 474)
        - WNET - Steven Salyer and Tom Anderson, May-November 1985 (Box 8, Folder 475)
        - Women and the Media, June-July 1975 (Box 8, Folder 476)
        - Women in Broadcasting, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 477)
        - World Administrative Radio Conference, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 478)
        - X-Z, 1974, 1979-1982, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 479)
      - Chronological Files, 2
        Subseries 2 is arranged by month, and thereunder by reverse chronology by day.
        Materials in Subseries 2 consist of office copies related to all outgoing correspondence generated by the Foundation staff.
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 480)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 481)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 482)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 483)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 484)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 485)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 486)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 487)
        - January-December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 488)
        - January-June 1976 (Box 8, Folder 489)
        - January-June 1976 (Box 8, Folder 490)
        - January-June 1976 (Box 8, Folder 491)
        - January-June 1976 (Box 8, Folder 492)
        - January-June 1976 (Box 8, Folder 493)
        - January-June 1976 (Box 8, Folder 494)
        - July-December 1976 (Box 9, Folder 495)
        - July-December 1976 (Box 9, Folder 496)
        - July-December 1976 (Box 9, Folder 497)
        - July-December 1976 (Box 9, Folder 498)
        - July-December 1976 (Box 9, Folder 499)
        - July-December 1976 (Box 9, Folder 500)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 501)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 502)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 503)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 504)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 505)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 506)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 507)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 508)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 509)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 510)
        - January-December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 511)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 512)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 513)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 514)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 515)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 516)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 517)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 518)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 519)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 520)
        - January-October 1978 (Box 9, Folder 521)
        - November-December 1978 (Box 10, Folder 522)
        - November-December 1978 (Box 10, Folder 523)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 524)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 525)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 526)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 527)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 528)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 529)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 530)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 531)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 532)
        - January-December 1979 (Box 10, Folder 533)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 534)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 535)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 536)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 537)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 538)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 539)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 540)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 541)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 542)
        - January-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 543)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 544)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 545)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 546)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 547)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 548)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 549)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 550)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 551)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 552)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 553)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 554)
        - January-October 1981 (Box 10, Folder 555)
        - January-December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 556)
        - January-December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 557)
        - January-December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 558)
        - January-December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 559)
        - January-December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 560)
        - January-December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 561)
        - January-December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 562)
        - January-December 1983 (Box 11, Folder 563)
        - January-December 1983 (Box 11, Folder 564)
        - January-December 1983 (Box 11, Folder 565)
        - January-December 1983 (Box 11, Folder 566)
        - January-December 1983 (Box 11, Folder 567)
        - January-December 1983 (Box 11, Folder 568)
        - January-December 1983 (Box 11, Folder 569)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 570)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 571)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 572)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 573)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 574)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 575)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 576)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 577)
        - January-December 1984 (Box 11, Folder 578)
        - January-November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 579)
        - January-November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 580)
        - January-November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 581)
        - January-November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 582)
        - January-November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 583)
        - January-November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 584)
        - December 1985 (Box 12, Folder 585)
        - January-December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 586)
        - January-December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 587)
        - January-December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 588)
        - January-December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 589)
        - January-December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 590)
        - January-December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 591)
        - January-December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 592)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 593)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 594)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 595)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 596)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 597)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 598)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 599)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 600)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 601)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 602)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 603)
        - January-December 1987 (Box 12, Folder 604)
        - January-May 1988 (Box 12, Folder 605)
        - January-May 1988 (Box 12, Folder 606)
        - January-May 1988 (Box 12, Folder 607)
        - January-May 1988 (Box 12, Folder 608)
        - January-May 1988 (Box 12, Folder 609)
        - June-December 1988 (Box 13, Folder 610)
        - June-December 1988 (Box 13, Folder 611)
        - June-December 1988 (Box 13, Folder 612)
        - June-December 1988 (Box 13, Folder 613)
        - June-December 1988 (Box 13, Folder 614)
        - June-December 1988 (Box 13, Folder 615)
        - January-June 1989 (Box 13, Folder 616)
        - January-June 1989 (Box 13, Folder 617)
        - January-June 1989 (Box 13, Folder 618)
        - January-June 1989 (Box 13, Folder 619)
        - January-June 1989 (Box 13, Folder 620)
        - January-June 1989 (Box 13, Folder 621)
    - Board of Directors, 1979-1989; 3; 1.2 Cubic Feet 1 box
      Subseries 1 - Minutes of Meetings
      - Minutes of Meetings, 1980-1989; 1
        - June 30, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - December 4, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - March 30, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - June 3, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - November 30, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - March 29, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - June 7, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - November 29, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - April 7, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - June 27, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - November 28, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - March 26, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - July 9, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - November 26, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - April 3, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - May 17, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - June 17, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - November 25, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - March 31, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - June 16, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - November 24, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - March 30, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - June 15, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - November 24, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - March 16, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - June 29, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - November 30, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        - March 22, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        - June 28, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
        - November 29, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        - Executive Committee, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
        - Finance Committee, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
        - Audit Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Meeting Agendas, 1979-1989; 2
        - November 29, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        - March 24, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        - June 30, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 36)
        - December 4, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
        - March 30, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
        - June 3, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
        - October 13, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 40)
        - November 30, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 41)
        - March 29, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 42)
        - June 7, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 43)
        - November 29, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 44)
        - April 7, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 45)
        - June 27, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
        - October 28, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
        - November 28, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 48)
        - March 26, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 49)
        - July 9, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 50)
        - November 26, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 51)
        - April 3, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 52)
        - June 17, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 53)
        - November 25, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 54)
        - March 31, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 55)
        - June 16, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 56)
        - November 24, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 57)
        - March 30, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 58)
        - June 15, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 59)
        - October 7, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 60)
        - November 24, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 61)
        - March 16, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 62)
        - June 29, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 63)
        - November 30, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 64)
        - March 22, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 65)
        - June 28, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 66)
        - Executive Committee, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- John Markle Personal Material (Accession 1), 3; 2 Cubic Feet
  This record group, received as part of Accession 1, is arranged in 5 series:
  Series 1 - Personal Material
  Series 2 - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation
  Series 3 - John Markle - Estate
  Series 4 - John Markle - Business
  Series 5 - Markle Handicraft School
  - Personal Material, 1884-1979; 1902-1937; 1; 0.5 Cubic Feet 2 boxes
    - Genealogy Correspondence, 1924-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Markle Family - Genealogy, 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "The Merkel, Merkle, Markle Freundschaft" - Part I - Norton W. Merkel, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "The Merkel, Merkle, Markle Freundschaft" - Part II - Norton W. Merkel, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "John Markle, Representative American" - Robert J. Spence, ed., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "John Markle, Representative American" - Correspondence Regarding Biography, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Articles Written by John Markle, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mary Robinson Markle Genealogy, 1925-1932 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1884-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Woodlawn Cemetery, 1924-1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Mary R. Markle - Will and Estate, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - John Markle - Will, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - John Markle - Will, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - John Markle - Obituary, July 11, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "The Book of the Presidents" - Charles H. Grosvenor, Washington, DC, 1902, Bound volume (Box 1, Volume 1)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
  - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation, 1927-1937; 2; 0.5 Cubic Feet 3 folders
    - Establishment, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Walter Hindennach, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Estate of John Markle, 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Specific to Foundation.
  - John Markle - Estate, 1922-1972 1922-1939; 3; 0.5 Cubic Feet 8 folders
    - July-December 1933 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Settlement of Account, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Settlement of Account, 1933-1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Securities, 1948-1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Worthless.
    - Charles McKendress - Mortgage, 1932-1947 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - J. M. Macleod - Trust, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Irene Power - Trust, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - John Markle - Business, 1925-1930; 4; 2 folders
    - Jeddo-Highland Coal Company, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Jeddo-Highland Coal Company, 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Markle Handicraft School, 1929-1949; 5; 2 folders
    - Markle Handicraft School, 1925-1936 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Markle Handicraft School, 1937-1949 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Markle Foundation photographs, 1064
  Photographs
  - Buildings (Box 56, Folder 683)
  - Portraits (Box 56, Folder 684)